# Christopher Mitchell

Colorado Springs, CO

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Christopher-Mitchell/7711eebb8f8a4efa

Objective: Full-time position as Project Engineer

Practical and professional focus on formulating long range goals and developing action plans to achieve desired outcomes.

Excellent technical and logistical capabilities, underscored by over twenty-five years of experience in engineering, operations management, and strategic planning resulting in the successful implementation of production plans.

## Work Experience

## **Electrical Engineering Contractor**

Kaman - Colorado, New Mexico, and Arizona January 2012 to Present

(Employers and Clients:

Saber Astronautics • Keysight • Kaman Precision Products · National Solar Observatory · Samtec Electronics ·

Secure SIGINT · Emerging Technology Ventures · Aerotek)

### **Electrical Engineering**

(Employers: Raytheon  $\cdot$  SEAKR Engineering  $\cdot$  SGT, Inc.  $\cdot$  ITT Industries) - Colorado January 1994 to December 2012

#### **Forest Products Mill Worker**

White Sands Forest Products - Alamogordo, NM January 1988 to December 1991

#### Management

Project Management

- # Over ten years of Project Management, Cost Estimation, and Technical Leadership for large scale, multifaceted production activities.
- # Experience building teams in order to execute tasks efficiently and according to overarching project objectives.
- # Experience driving team activities and refactoring resources in order to achieve schedule, production, and quality goals.
- # Able to maintain standards of safety and comply with established health, safety and management systems requirements.
- # Able to understand the mechanisms of running a business, and translate high level operational goals into detailed implementation plans.

## Education

## **Bachelor of Electrical Engineering in Electrical Engineering**

NEW MEXICO STATE UNIVERSITY - Las Cruces, NM 1994

## Skills

- Able to understand and interpret technical drawings and specifications for various disciplines.
- Able to track production activities and present relevant reports and documentation in a concise manner.
- Microsoft Office Suite (including MS Project)
- Able to clearly coordinate and communicate work objectives to subordinate workers.
- Frequent contributor (authoring and co-authoring) to the generation of domain specific trade publications, work proposals, engineering documents, and training materials.